<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on ItsNikhil</title>
    <link>https://itsnikhil.github.io/blog/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on ItsNikhil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>ItsNikhil</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://itsnikhil.github.io/blog/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithm behind TNB Analysis</title>
      <link>https://itsnikhil.github.io/blog/posts/algorithm-behind-tnb-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsnikhil.github.io/blog/posts/algorithm-behind-tnb-analysis/</guid>
      <description>TNB or thenewboston is a digital cryptocurrency network which is being developed by Bucky Roberts and open source community of which I am part of. There are thousands of registered accounts which will increase rapidly in future. At the time of writing this article there are 90 JSON files. My task was to process each of these JSON files and output results providing insights like total coins distribution over time period, total number of accounts, richest account information, wealth distribution, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is pythonic way the better way?</title>
      <link>https://itsnikhil.github.io/blog/posts/is-pythonic-way-the-better-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itsnikhil.github.io/blog/posts/is-pythonic-way-the-better-way/</guid>
      <description>Here I have shared my thoughts on some of the pythonic way coding style. These are not design patterns (which are best practices used by experienced object-oriented software developers) of any sort, just some ways of writing code differently or I should say more pythonic.
If you might not already know - Python is an interpreted, interactive, object-oriented programming language. But more importantly, Python is a programming language that lets you work more quickly and integrate your systems more effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>